Air date, unknown.
The impossible has happened.
It would take days
to recount the events I've witnessed.
So, settle in.
It all began...
Quiet, you! This court-martial
is now in session.
The honorably sexy
Zapp Brannigan residing.
Bring in the accused.
Oh, my.
Philip J. Fry,
you stand accused
of traveling to the forbidden
planet Omega 3,
a crime punishable by 12
concurrent death sentences.
- Do you understand the charges?
- One beep for "yes," two beeps for "no."
Yes. So noted. Do you plead guilty?
Double yes. Guilty!
I will now
carry out the sentence. Kif, my gun.
Wait!
He pled "not guilty."
Order!
Order in the court!
Very well then, Mr. Fry. Please recount
the events that led you to be guilty.
The professor said he was taking
a brief nap,
so we only have time for six movies.
Let's take these six Jim Carrey movies
and record over them!
You know what six movies average out
to be really good?
The first six Star Trek movies!
Everybody hit the deck!
Shh!
Those words are forbidden.
What words? Star Trek?
- Shh!
- Shut your gills!
That sound. It's patrol car 718! Hide him!
The court is intrigued.
Perhaps we could hear more
about these forbidden words
from someone with
a sexily seductive voice.
With pleasure. You see, the show was
banned after the Star Trek wars.
You mean the vast migration
of Star Wars fans?
Uh, no. That was
the Star Wars trek.
By the 23rd century,
Star Trek fandom
had evolved from a loose
association of nerdswith skin problems
into a full-blown religion.
And Scotty beamed them
to the Klingon ship
where they would
be no Tribble at all.
All power
to the engines.
As country after country
fellunder its influence,
world leaders became threatened
by the movement's power.
And so the Trekkies
were executed
in the manner
most befitting virgins.
- Whoa!
- He's dead, Jim.
He's dead, Jim.
Finally, the sacred texts
were banned.
The last copies of
the 79episodes and six movies
were dumped on the
forbidden world Omega 3,
along with that blooper reel
where the door doesn'tclose all the way.
Thus, Star Trek was forever
scoured from human memory.
Another classic science-fiction show
canceled before its time.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
I've never heard of such a brutal
and shocking injustice
that I cared so little about.
- Next witness!
- Bender the Robot, please take the stand.
She's all yours, buddy.
I'd only met
the defendant, Fry, once,
but I knew
he was up to no good.
- Please use the beeps.
- Oh!
Mr. Nimoy! I came as soon
as I heard what happened centuries ago.
I can't believe
your show was banned.
I have absolutely
no idea what you're talking about.
You know... 1966?
Seventy-nine episodes?
About 30 good ones?
Oh, really. I've done too many things
to remember one particular TV series.
But if... If you want to
discuss my books of poetry...
Come on! Remember that episode
where you got high on spores
and smacked Kirk around?
No. Perhaps you're thinking of my
one-man show about Vincent van Spock.
I... I... I mean van Gogh.
Damn!
Aha!
You can't escape it.
Oh, you're right.
I can't.
Uh...
Geez, don't get upset.
I mean, okay,
I outwitted you, but...
No. It's my
fellow cast members.
Three hundred years ago,
they left Earth behind.
This planet doesn't
appreciate us anymore, Leonard.
Bill, you are,
and always shall be, my friend.
But I just signed
a six-month lease on my apartment.
I can't walk away from
a commitment like that.
Farewell, my friend.
Oh!
Why did the world turn its back
on our obvious greatness?
I'm literally
angry with rage!
Your costars may be gone,
but we can still get those episode tapes
back for the whole world to see!
Come on!
Yes! Front row!
You can't go to Omega 3!
It's forbidden!
I forbid you!
But we have to! The world needs Star Trek
to give people hope for the future!
But it's set 800 years
in the past.
Yeah! Why is this
so important to you?
'Cause it...
It taught me so much.
Like how you should
accept people,
whether they be black,
white, Klingon, or even female.
But most importantly,
when I didn't have any friends,
it... It made me feel
like maybe I did.
Well, that is
touchingly pathetic.
I guess I can't
let you go alone.
I'll go too...
With Leonard's permission, of course.
We're entering the Omega system.
Warning. You are nowin forbidden space.
Forbidden, schur-schmidden.
What are they gonna do,
write a letter?
Ooh, I'm so scared.
I've lost control of the ship!
Lost control of the ship!
Oh, dip!
Dip, indeed.
It's all stuff from that forbidden show.
So many cardboard sets.
So many memories.
- If only the others...
- I guess that's my cue.
- Bill!
- L-Dog!
- Hey! This is wonderful!
- Oh, man.
- I feel like hugging you.
- Well, I would, except you have no body.
And we're both men.
Nichelle! George! Walter!
DeForrest!
Welshie!
Welshie?
We did some musical reunion specials
in the 2200s.
But the guy who played Scotty
had trouble yodeling.
Ever since then,
Welshie has been a welcome participant
in our escapades.
Aye!
I can't believe it!
How'd you all end up here?
We were on our way to Welshie's cousin's
house to stay in the guest room
when our ship was pulled down to this
planet and crashed, just like yours.
When we woke up,
we had these bodies.
Say it in Russian.
Ven vee voke up,
vee had these wah-dies.
Eee!
Now say nuclear "wessels"!
- No!
- We love it here.
Everything is provided for us,
and we never age.
Check out these abs.
- Yowza!
- But who's doing all this for you?
You know, we never thought about it.
We're famous celebrities.
- We're used to this sort of treatment.
- It is I!
Whoa! What a cheesy effect!
I'm not an effect!
You doubt my power?
I do!
Aye!
Welshie!
This court will now hear some
very sensual testimony
from this court's ex-lover,
Turanga Leela.
Go yourself.
Behold another power,
different from
the one you saw earlier!
Hey! A body!
Buff, tan...
Yeah.
This is mine, all right.
All right, you gas.
What's the deal?
Centuries ago, the videotaped adventures
of the Enterprise crew
rained down upon my planet.
Over and over
I watched them,
especially the five
with the energy beings.
I am Melllvar!
Seer of the Tapes! Knower of the Episodes!
Tremble before my encyclopedic
knowledge of Star Trek!
Tremble? I laugh.
Nobody knows more about Star Trek than me!
I beg to differ!
Long have I waited
for the one who played Spock.
At last we can begin.
Cool!
A Star Trek convention!
Uh... Uh, Melllvar?
Can you give us some idea
of how long
this is going to last?
Until time stops.
- What?
- You can't do this!
Now, we have
a full schedule of events.
- Uh, can people who hate Star Trek leave?
- Good question.
No. You have to stay even longer!
Um... Uh...
Sign it to Melllvar.
Melllvar has three "L's".
I think I've done enough conventions
to know how to spell Melllvar.
- Say "nerd"!
- Nerd!
I'm Slim Shady.
Yes.
I'm the real Shady.
All you other Slim Shadys
are just imitating.
So, won't the real Slim Shady
please stand up?
Please stand up.
How can you do
a spoken-word version of a rap song?
He found a way.
For 100 quatloos, who did the captain
maroon on Ceti Alpha Five?
Khan!
Uh, Khan?
- Correct!
- My button has broken!
The trivia contest is ended.
I now have a surprise.
You will perform
a fan script
written by
the ultimate Trek fan!
- You have my fan script?
- I meant me! Melllvar's the ultimate fan!
Oh. I was confused because the scoreboard
says something different.
Trivia contest over! Take your scripts!
We have limited
rehearsal time.
Now, I didn't make enough
copies of the script,
so George and Walter
will have to share.
Uh... You probably don't want us
to see you rehearsing,
or it'll give away the ending.
That's right!
The ending must not be ruined!
- We'll go wait in the ship.
- Okay.
Not till I get
my 600 quatloos!
This is wrong.
We shouldn't have abandoned them there.
I don't know.
I'm feelin' pretty good about it.
I didn't want to leave them either, Fry.
But what were we supposed to do?
Well, usually on the show, someone would
come up with a complicated plan,
then explain it
with a simple analogy.
Hmm. If we can reroute
engine power through the primary weapons
and reconfigure them
to Melllvar's frequency,
that should overload
his electro-quantum structure.
Like putting too much air
in a balloon!
Of course!
It's so simple!
"Alas, my ship,
whom I love like a woman,
"is... Disabled."
- Oh, Lord.
- "Fascinating, Captain.
"And logical too.
Yet we need some help."
"Look, Captain.
Melllvar will help us."
"Captain, I wope he will
welp our vessel."
Wessel!
You're not acting hard enough!
Melllvar, you have to respect your actors.
When I directed Star Trek IV, I got
a magnificent performance out of Bill
because I respected him
so much.
And when I directed
Star Trek V,
I got a magnificent performance
out of me because I respected me so much.
Okay! I'm done "recafoobelling"
the energy-motron!
Or whatever!
Fire!
"My, what a handsome
energy creature you are.
"I love you."
Hey, you wrote it!
It's not working!
He's drawing strength from our weapons!
Like a balloon, and...
Something bad happens!
Yep.
So, uh,
how's rehearsal going?
Lousy. Here I've been
admiring a bunch of actors, while you,
a crew of genuine space heroes,
risked your lives to save them.
Hey, we've done
heroic things too.
Yeah.
In the third season, I kissed Shatner.
Silence! My whole world
has turned upside down.
I have but one option.
- Keep them and let us go?
- No!
To determine who is more worthy
of my fanatical devotion,
I shall pit you against each other
in armed combat... To the death!
Where'd you get
an idiotic idea like that?
Episodes 19, 46,
56 and 77!
Great list.
Except you forgot episode 66.
I was getting to that one!
So Melllvar ordered
a battle to the death.
I assume no one survived?
Can we get on with this?
My foot's getting tired.
This will be your standard
battle to the death.
The only weapons...
Whatever you can find.
But I warn you.
Do nothing
until I have signaled
the start of combat.
Okay, start.
I don't have much experience at fighting,
except with you guys.
I have an idea. Wasn't there an episode
where I threw my shoe at the enemy?
You mean Doohan?
Whoever it was,
I did it like this. Yaah!
- Ow!
- My foot's cold.
There. We can
make these into spears.
And we can tie these caterpillars together
to make bow strings for bows and arrows.
And we can use this machine gun
to shoot them!
Yee-haw!
That was fun.
What if I distract them
with my famous fan dance?
Oh, that's good,
good, good, good. And then, George,
- you give them a karate chop.
- I find that offensive.
Just because I'm of Japanese ancestry,
you assume I know karate.
Have I ever
led you to believe I have studied karate?
Well, no.
But you never talk about yourself.
Maybe if you showed
a little interest.
Well, here goes nothing.
Hello, boys.
Whoa!
Hyah!
Aah!
- There's no right way to hit a woman.
- Then do it the wrong way.
Fine.
Yeee-oh-ho!
Is that all you got? Hyah!
- Come on, Walter!
- Take that!
It hurts.
Let's see if this
actually works.
- Ow! Ow! Ow!
- Aah! My face!
My face too!
May I?
Hyah!
Excellent.
Leela, please.
This is exactly what Melllvar wants.
We're just pawns in his
diabolical game of checkers.
Can't we resolve
our differences some other way?
Melllvar!
Dinnertime!
Aw, but, Mom!
I'm playin' with my collectibles!
Now!
All this time,
we thought he was a powerful super-being.
- Yet he was just a child.
- He's not a child! He's 34!
All right, Koenig!
I've wanted to do this for years!
Bender, wait! This is our chance
to escape before Melllvar comes back!
But we all need
to work together.
- I love you so much.
- Hello.
- We've decided to work together.
- Yeah, so did they.
Now, how do we escape?
We can't use our ship.
We have life support,
but the engines are wrecked.
Ironic, because our engines work,
but our life support systems don't.
- Hey. If your engines work...
- And your life support systems work...
Stop! You're just
goin' around in circles!
Think, Fry. Think.
Everyone's depending on you.
We're too heavy!
You guys need to lose some weight. Fast!
Fish.
Look! Leonard!
We're light enough to keep the tapes!
- Isn't that great?
- I'm living in a gefilte fish jar.
We did it!
Melllvar's got a spaceship!
Yes!
In mint condition!
And you made me take it
out of the package!
The Nimbus!
We're saved!
You're under arrest.
Prepare to be boarded.
So I boarded you, huh?
Uh, what happened next?
You started this stupid
court-martial!
Now if you don't mind,
we're still fighting Melllvar.
One more hit, and we're done for!
Let's take him out with us.
Do you guys have a self-destruct code?
Like destruct sequence
1-A, 2-B, 3...
Thanks a lot, Takei!
Now everybody knows!
If I can't have the original
cast of Star Trek, no one will!
Prepare to die!
Wait! If they mean that much to you,
why do you want to kill them?
Because I... I...
I don't know what I'd do
without them.
Melllvar, you can't
let a TV show be your whole life.
You can do anything you want.
Look at Walter Koenig.
After Star Trek,
he became an actor.
Not just an actor
but a well-rounded person
with my own friends
and credit cards and keys.
Well, I... Guess I could move out
of my parents' basement.
- Maybe get a temp job.
- Whoa, whoa. One step at a time.
I thank you, Fry.
You know, you and I
are of a kind.
In a different reality,
I could have called you... Friend.
Episode 10.
"Balance of Terror."
More like episode nine,
loser!
In your face!
Victory is mine!
I wonder, my friends.
Was he really such
an evil energy gas?
He did give us
eternal youth.
Twenty-four hour
laundromat.
A full assortment of rum,
both spiced and regular.
Truly,
it was a paradise.
And all you had to put up with was
one really annoying Star Trek fan.
Let's get the hell
out of here.